詹森 · 兰斯托夫: 另一种看法是，它是一个进步的 Web 应用程序
&gt;&gt; Jason Lengstorf: Another way to think
of it is that it's a Progressive Web App
发电机。
generator.
所以因为我们正在运送静态资产，在反应应用程序中重新水化,
So because we are shipping static assets
that rehydrate in the react apps,
这也意味着使用诸如服务工作者之类的东西可以让我们离线捕捉
that also means that using things like
service workers allows us to catch offline
然后上传一个显能者插件，用于这两种事情
versions and upload a manifester plug-ins
for both of those things that make it
相对直接地使你的应用程序可以离线使用盖茨比。
relatively straight forward to make your
apps available offline using Gatsby.
这显然不能解决客户网站的问题，但是
That obviously isn't gonna solve
the client site problem, but
它将使所有的构建时间数据和所有静态资产可用，因此
it will make all of the build time data
and all of your static assets available so
有人可以把它保存下来以备后用。
that someone could save it offline for
use later.
最终，盖茨比的目标是让正确的事情变得简单。
Ultimately, the goal with Gatsby is to
make the right thing the easy thing.
我们的想法是设置好的默认值，这样如果有人
The idea is to set good defaults so
that if somebody just
就这样，他们会得到一个好结果。
leaves it as is out of the box,
they're gonna get a good result.
另一种说法是，我们试图设计工具
Another way to say that is that we're
trying to design tools so that somebody
他完全处于截稿压力之下，走了书中所有的捷径,
who is completely under deadline pressure
and takes every shortcut in the book,
为使用者提供了一个绝佳的体验。
delivers an excellent experience
to the people using the website.
所以盖茨比在引擎盖下面设置了很好的缺省值。
So Gatsby under the hood
is setting good defaults.
它是按照紫色图案设计的，如果你跟着艾迪 · 奥斯马尼，或者
It's following the purple pattern,
which if you follow Addy Osmani, or
的 Chrome 开发团队,
the Google Chrome dev team,
我认为是谁能把这一切都是关于喜欢。
I think is who could put this
out which is all about like.
如何构造预加载和渲染的数据请求
How to structure data request for
pre-loading and rendering in
背景和很多东西让它在网站上表现得更好。
the background and lots of things that
make it more performing on the website.
我不想谈细节,
I'm not gonna go into the details of that,
不过这个紫色图案值得一看。
the purple pattern is
worth looking up though.
它也只生成静态资产，这再次从服务器中删除
It also generates only static assets
which again taking the server out of
方程式,
the equation,
这样用户获取数据就少了一个跳跃。
that's one less hop that your users
have to make to get to the data.
然后 Gatsby 会优化一个延迟装载的资产，所以你可以使用，而不是
And then Gatsby will optimize an lazy-load
assets, so you can take, instead of
你上传到博客的一张3mb 的手机图片。
a single three megabyte image off of your
phone that you've uploaded to your blog.
这将得到压缩，削减，变成适当大小的图像为
That'll get compressed, cut down,
turned into the right size image for
当它出现在 viewport 中时，它才会被加载,
the viewport loading it, and it only gets
loaded when it shows up in the viewport,
这将为您的用户节省兆字节的数据传输和
which saves your users
megabytes of data transfer and
如果他们不滚动到页面的那一部分，可能根本不会载入。
potentially never loads it at all if they
don't scroll to that part of the page.
它也会使第三方数据正常化。
It'll normalize third party data as well.
因此，我们再次讨论了通过 GraphQL 进行数据访问。
So again, we talked about
the data access through GraphQL.
通过这样做，您不必弄清楚如何异步加载
By doing that, you don't have to
figure out how to asynchronously load
一堆第三方的 API，并尝试使性能。
a bunch of third party API's and
try to make that performance.
如果你最终处于进行大量异步调用的情况下,
If you end up in a situation where you're
making lots of asynchronous calls,
你可能会想使用异步等待。
you're probably gonna be
tempted to use async await.
但是如果你使用了 async await，并且你没有像 promise dot all 那样设置,
But if you use async await, and you're
not setting up like a promise dot all,
然后它们实际上是按顺序运行的。
then they're actually blocking and
running sequentially.
所以不经意间，你会让你的页面变得非常慢。
So inadvertently,
you'll make your pages really slow.
通过将这些数据规范化为 GraphQL，盖茨比可以为您处理所有这些数据。
By normalizing that data into GraphQL,
Gatsby handles all of that for you.
所以你实际上不需要考虑如何快速获取数据。
So you don't actually have to think
about how to get that data in quickly.
因为你是在构建的时候做的，所以作为一个开发人员你会感到痛苦,
And because you're doing it at build time,
you feel that pain as a developer,
如果你因为构建缓慢而做了一些不能执行的事情。
if you do something that's not
performing because the build is slow.
但是产生的静态资产速度很快。
But the static assets that
get generated are fast.
因此，如果你做了一些愚蠢的事情，你的用户不会感到痛苦
And so your users don't feel the pain
if you do something silly with
你的数据管理。
your data management.
我的意思是，你显然想要解决这个问题，但这成为你的问题，而不是他们的，对不对？
I mean, you wanna fix that obviously, but
it becomes your problem not theirs, right?
另一件我认为很重要的事情是,
The other thing that I think is
really important about this is that,
而盖茨比有很多的观点，建立了一系列的默认值。
while Gatsby has a lot of opinions and
sets up a bunch of defaults.
它也给了你巨大的控制力。
It also gives you a huge
amount of control.
所以你可以直接进入 Webpack 配置,
So you can get all the way
down to the Webpack config,
你可以一直到巴别塔的配置。
you can get all the way
down to the Babel config.
但重要的是，盖茨比使用了我创立的一个模型
But the thing that's important is that
Gatsby uses a model that I I've started
称之为复杂性的渐进揭示。
calling progressive
disclosure of complexity.
我不认为这个术语是我编造的，但是我把它加进去了。
I don't think I made up that term but
I've co-opted it.
也就是说，当你想要修改某个东西时,
Which is the idea that,
when you want to modify something,
你只需要弹出你想修改的部分。
you should only have to eject
the piece that you want to modify.
我们可能都已经看到这一点，当你使用某种锅炉镀工具
We've probably all seen this when you
use some kind of a boiler plated tool
它可以做任何我们想做的事情，然后我们遇到了一个边缘案例
that it does all the things that we
want and then we hit an edge case and
突然间，所有的配置都由我们来管理。
suddenly, all of the config
is managed by us.
整个应用程序变得客观，现在任何发生在上游的变化,
The entire app becomes objective, and
now any change that happens upstream,
我们必须手动迁移。
we have to manually migrate.
这其中有很多痛苦的地方。
There are a lot of pain
points involved in that.
所以盖茨比试图通过一次只展示一部分作品来摆脱这一点。
So Gatsby tries to get rid of that by only
exposing pieces one section at a time.
如果你对巴别塔进行了调整,
If you make a Babel adjustment,
你不需要排出整个盖茨比建造的管道。
you don't have to eject
the entire Gatsby build pipeline.
你只是注入了一小块巴别塔配置。
You're just injecting that one
little piece of Babel config.
总结一下，盖茨比速度很快，所有的方法都很重要,
So, to kind of recap this, Gatsby is
fast and all the ways that matter,
作为开发人员，它能让你更快，让你更快。
it makes you faster as a developer,
it makes you faster.
您的用户将看到的体验更快。
The experience that your
users will see is faster.
开始的速度很快，发布和重复的速度也很快。
And it's fast to get started,
fast to ship and iterate.
这些都是非常重要的事情。
And those are all really important things.
并允许您从任何地方带入数据，因为它可以使用该文件
And lets you bring in your data from
anywhere because it can use the file
系统、 API、软件即服务。
system, API, software as a service.
它不会限制你作为一个开发人员可以构建什么或者
It doesn't restrict you as
a developer on what you can build or
你可以从哪里开始建造。
where you can build it from.
默认情况下，它通过默认设置良好的防护栏来做正确的事情,
It does the right thing by default by
setting up good guard rails in defaults,
你可以省去大部分的麻烦，仍然可以得到一个好的结果。
you're able to cut most of the corners and
still get a good result.
我认为这可能是对我来说最重要的事情。
And I think this is probably
the most important thing for me.
如果我有一个愚蠢的想法的话，盖茨比实际上又让我觉得网络开发很有趣了
Gatsby actually made web development fun
for me again, if I have a silly idea for
一个项目，我实际上现在建立它。
a project, I actually build it now.
因为在我完成一个 web pack 配置的一半之前
Because before I would get halfway
through a web pack config, and
然后我就会灰心丧气，再也不想这么做了。
then I would get disheartened, and
I wouldn't wanna do it anymore.
所以在《了不起的盖茨比》中，当你说《了不起的盖茨比》采用了你的模板,
And so with Gatsby, when you just
say Gatsby new use your template,
它只是给你一些东西，你可以运行盖茨比发展。
it will just give you something that
you can run Gatsby development.
它已经在浏览器中运行了，我马上就开始编写 UI 代码。
It's in the browser and it's working and
I'm immediately writing UI code.
我不是在试图弄明白如何让我的样板文件如此工作
I'm not trying to figure out how
to get my boilerplate to work so
我可以运送一些东西。
that I can ship something.
这就是大致情况，对吧？
So, that's kind of the overview, right?
这就是为什么《了不起的盖茨比》值得一看的原因
That's my pitch on why Gatsby
is worth looking into and
为什么它值得认真对待，作为一个网络技术。
why it's worth taking
seriously as a web technology.
但是兔子洞越陷越深，这就是我们今天要做的。
But the rabbit hole goes so much deeper
and that's what we're gonna do today.